<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Rocker Project on Rocker Project</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Rocker Project on Rocker Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Policies</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites You should be generally numerically literate, and some prior programming experience will be helpful. Students new to programming might find Hands on Programming with R to be helpful. Students with significant experience in programming and statistical analysis should find themselves well prepared but should find plenty still to learn in each lesson.
Instructional Methods As a flipped classroom, students are provided with either reading or video material that they are expected to view/read prior to class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/conduct/</guid>
      <description>Contributor Covenant Code of Conduct Our Pledge In the interest of fostering an open and welcoming environment, we as contributors and maintainers pledge to making participation in our project and our community a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of age, body size, disability, ethnicity, sex characteristics, gender identity and expression, level of experience, education, socio-economic status, nationality, personal appearance, race, religion, or sexual identity and orientation.
Our Standards Examples of behavior that contributes to creating a positive environment include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/signup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/signup/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christian Louboutin</title>
      <link>/profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profile/</guid>
      <description> timeline Climate Change    bug_report Ecological simulation    directions_boat Overfishing    my_location Spatial movement    trending_down Mass Extinctions    cloud Cloud computing    Concepts CO2 concentration Global mean temperature Sea level rise Land ice sheet melt Arctic sea ice cover   Skills  Data wrangling: plain text formats Tidy data (intro) Data visualization Smoothing     Left Column  right column    Wide entry    unit 4 L  unit 4 R    unit 5 L  unit 5 R    unit 5 L  unit 5 R       </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending images</title>
      <link>/use/extending/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use/extending/</guid>
      <description>Rocker images provide a few utility functions to streamline this process, including the littler scripts which provide a concise syntax for installing packages in Dockerfiles, e.g.
RUN install2.r pkg1 pgk2 pkg3 ...  Users writing their own Dockerfiles are encouraged to follow the same practices as the Rocker Project, such as the Dockerfile Best Practices, the use of automated builds, and when appropriate, versioned tags. Users can ensure their automated builds are rebuilt every time the relevant upstream Dockerfile is updated by using build triggers on Docker Hub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing containers</title>
      <link>/use/managing_containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use/managing_containers/</guid>
      <description>The simplest tools to monitor containers are docker log and docker stats commands.
Cleaning up stale instances Most of the examples shown here include the use of the --rm flag, which will cause this container to be removed after it has exited. By default, a container that is stopped (i.e. exited from) is not removed, and can be resumed later using docker start, be saved as a new docker image, or have files copied from it to the host (see the offical Docker documentation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Users</title>
      <link>/use/managing_users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use/managing_users/</guid>
      <description>RStudio-based instances now always require a custom password as an environmental variable -e:
docker run -d -p 8787:8787 -e PASSWORD=clever-custom-password rocker/rstudio Without a password, the container will exit with a warning message instead.
RStudio without authentication If you are certain you are running in a secure environment (e.g. not a publicly accessible server such as AWS instance), you can disable authentication for RStudio by setting an environmental variable DISABLE_AUTH=true, e.g.:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking: tips and tricks</title>
      <link>/use/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use/networking/</guid>
      <description>httpsHTTPS Any RStudio instance on a remote server is accessed over an unencrypted http by default (though RStudio encrypts the password entered to log in through client-side javascript.) The easiest way to connect over a secure https connection is to use a reverse proxy server, such as Caddy. To establish an encrypted https connection, you must first have control of a registered domain name: https cannot be used when connecting directly to a given ip address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other topics</title>
      <link>/use/other_topics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use/other_topics/</guid>
      <description>selecting the BLAS implementation used by R By default rocker/r-ver uses the OpenBLAS (http://www.openblas.net) implementation for Linear Algebra (cf https://cran.r-project.org/doc/manuals/r-release/R-admin.html#BLAS). But it is possible to switch for the reference BLAS implementation (http://www.netlib.org/blas/) (as provided by the Debian package libblas-dev) using the Shared BLAS setup (cf https://cran.r-project.org/doc/manuals/r-release/R-admin.html#Shared-BLAS).
checking which BLAS is in use You can see the current BLAS configuration in your image by using sessionInfo() from the R console; e.g.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducibility</title>
      <link>/use/reproducibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use/reproducibility/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shared Volumes</title>
      <link>/use/shared_volumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use/shared_volumes/</guid>
      <description>A common configuration with Rocker containers is to share volumes between the container and the host filesystem. This allows the container to access and modify local files in directories you specify. In this way, the container can be treated as ephemeral while files you create will persist after the container is destroyed. Because the container only has access to files within the directories you specify, this can also prevent a user from accidentally modifying unrelated files on the file system when using software inside the container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singularity</title>
      <link>/use/singularity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use/singularity/</guid>
      <description>Singularity is useful for running containers as an unprivileged user, especially in multi-user environments like High-Performance Computing clusters. Rocker images can be imported and run using Singularity, with optional custom password support.
Importing a Rocker Image Use the singularity pull command to import the desired Rocker image from Docker Hub into a SquashFS (compressed, read-only) image:
singularity pull --name rstudio.simg docker://rocker/rstudio:latest If additional Debian software packages are needed, see the Singularity documentation for building a writable image or writable sandbox directory (note that sudo privileges are required).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rocker Images: choosing a container</title>
      <link>/images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/images/</guid>
      <description>The rocker project provides a collection of containers suited for different needs. find a base image to extend or images with popular software and optimized libraries pre-installed. Get the latest version or a reproducibly fixed environment.
The versioned stack This stack builds on stable Debian releases (debian:8 for versions &amp;lt; 3.4.1, debian:9 after). Images in this stack accept a version tag specifying which version of R is desired, e.g. rocker/rstudio:3.4.0 for R 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write the best title for your page.</title>
      <link>/landing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/landing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>